# Hans Walter Behrens

Summary Mobile: +1 310 347 7619

I am a third-year PhD student and Dean's Fellow, with extensive professional experience. I've worked in and managed teams, and have highly polished communication skills. My research focus is on distributed systems and scalable federated services, as well as techniques for privacy preservation and decentralized decision-making.

# **EDUCATION**

Experience

•	Arizona State University  Doctor in Philosophy (PhD), Computer Science (GPA: 4.00/4.00)	Tempe, AZ 2016 - 2021
•	University of California, Irvine Bachelor of Science (BSc), Information & Computer Science	Irvine, CA 2004 – 2007

# Arizona State University

Tempe, AZ

Dean's Fellow, Graduate Research Assistant, & Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug 2016 - Present

Email: hw@behrens.cc

- Dean's Fellowship Awarded a prestigious Dean's Fellowship, a 4-year paid position reserved for the most promising PhD students from each incoming class.
- Instructor of Record Sole instructor for an introductory engineering course (ASU 101), responsible for curriculum design, lecture delivery, and grade evaluation of 130 undergraduate students.
- Independent Research Designed and conducted a personal research agenda, under the Center for Assured and Scalable Data Engineering (CASCADE), to explore novel ideas in the intersection of scalability and security.
- DataStorm Successfully managed a team of graduate and undergraduate students in achieving our ambitious research goals, and leading to a successful top-tier publication of our complex distributed system.

## Canela Software, Inc.

Temecula, CA

Chief Technical Officer & other positions

Jan 2008 - July 2016

- **Personal Growth** During my time here, I worked tenaciously to rise from entry-level engineer to the executive team, via continuous technical excellence, clear and persuasive communication, and persistent adaptability.
- LiveCloud Architected a novel cloud database from scratch, oversaw and participated in its implementation, and reduced development overhead by almost 75% while simplifying cloud deployments.
- SpiceKit Proposed, designed, and implemented a modular software licensing system, increasing company-wide revenue by 14% YOY, while also reducing administrative and accounting overhead by nearly 50%.

### PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

- Adversarially-Resistant On-Demand Topic Channels for Wireless Sensor Networks HW Behrens and KS Candan, SRDS 2018 (Research Track)
- DataStorm-FE: A Data- and Decision-Flow and Coordination Engine for Coupled Simulation Ensembles HW Behrens et al., VLDB 2018 (Demonstration Track)
- Lightweight Authentication of Fault-Tolerant Topic-Channel Queries in Distributed Systems HW Behrens and KS Candan, HPDC 2018 (Consortium Track)

### Honors & Awards

- Upsilon Pi Epsilon (*UPE*), Computing Honors Society, Founding President.
- Phi Kappa Phi  $(\Phi K \Phi)$ , Graduate Honors Society, Member.
- Eta Kappa Nu (HKN), IEEE Honors Society, Member.
- Nora J. Folkenflik Memorial Essay Prize, for outstanding written communication.

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

- Conference Volunteer: 2017: CODASPY; 2018: HPDC
- Conference Reviewer: 2017: ASONAM, TKDE; 2018: EDBT, DASFAA, KDD, EUROPAR, TKDE